【The fate that cannot be liberated】
[해방될 수 없는 운명]
[Episode 16]
[16화]
It's a pity to marry
결혼하기가 아쉽네요
I had a falling out with Jia Lin four years ago.
저는 4년 전에 Jia Lin과 사이가 나빠졌습니다.
Your Majesty, what do you mean?
폐하, 무슨 말씀이신가요?
I'm planning to
나는 ~할 계획이다
try again.
다시 시도하십시오.
For His Majesty and Miss He?
폐하와 Miss He를 위해?
Isn't that appropriate?
적절하지 않나요?
When did I say it was for myself?
내가 언제 나를 위한 것이라고 말했나요?
When did I mention Jiuling?
내가 언제 Jiuling을 언급했습니까?
My brother is a bloodthirsty and violent man
내 동생은 피에 굶주린 폭력적인 남자야
Who tortured and killed several concubines
여러 명의 첩을 고문하고 살해한 사람
When he was still the crown prince.
그가 아직 왕세자였을 때.
Now he has been deposed
이제 그는 해임되었습니다
and was imprisoned in his mansion.
그리고 그의 저택에 투옥되었습니다.
It had eaten away at his psyche.
그것은 그의 정신을 잠식했습니다.
If I want to find him a suitable marriage
그 사람에게 적합한 결혼 생활을 찾고 싶다면
to improve his status
그의 지위를 향상시키기 위해
and bring him peace,
그에게 평화를 가져다주시고,
Isn't this a good idea?
좋은 생각 아닌가요?
what do you think?
어떻게 생각하나요?
That's great.
훌륭해요.
Are you talking about Princess Jialing Xilan?
Jialing Xilan 공주에 대해 이야기하고 있습니까?
Your Majesty?
폐하?
No.
아니요.
- Another one. - Another one?
- 다른 것. - 다른 것?
I will let Jiuling take revenge.
Jiuling이 복수하도록하겠습니다.
After its completion,
완료 후,
I will take her
나는 그녀를 데려갈 것이다
come back to me.
나에게 돌아와.
Miss.
놓치다.
Why are you standing outside?
왜 밖에 서 있나요?
I just gave Mr. Rong medicine.
방금 롱 씨에게 약을 줬어요.
He kicked me out.
그는 나를 쫓아 냈습니다.
I don't know what he was doing in there alone.
그 사람이 거기서 혼자 뭘 하고 있었는지 모르겠어요.
You'd better check him out.
그 사람을 확인해 보는 게 좋을 것 같아요.
Rong Yu,
유 롱,
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
I also brought the snacks you wanted.
원하시는 간식도 가져왔습니다.
Rong Yu, open the door.
유영 씨, 문을 열어주세요.
You asked them, didn't you?
당신이 그들에게 물었죠, 그렇죠?
Don't you want to try it?
시도해 보고 싶지 않으세요?
Rong Yu, come out.
유롱 씨, 나오세요.
Rong Yu.
유 롱.
I'm really worried about you.
나는 정말로 당신이 걱정됩니다.
- Take it. - What are you doing?
- 가져. - 뭐하세요?
you you? ? ?
당신은? ? ?
- It's too long. - What do you mean?
- 너무 길어. - 무슨 뜻이에요?
Are you saying it took me too long to come back?
내가 돌아오기까지 너무 오랜 시간이 걸렸다는 거야?
Then why don't you open the door?
그럼 문을 열어보는 게 어때?
Are you trying to make me worry?
나를 걱정하게 만들려는 거야?
how dare you?
어떻게 감히?
Now you dare to mess with me.
이제 감히 나한테 장난을 치는구나.
I originally planned to
원래는 그럴 계획이었는데
But now I don't want to do this anymore.
하지만 이제는 더 이상 이런 일을 하고 싶지 않습니다.
I'm going to make some soup.
나는 수프를 만들 예정이다.
Oh my goodness!
맙소사!
You scared Zhanping away
당신은 Zhanping을 겁주어서 쫓아냈어요
Let me see your hands.
손 좀 보여주세요.
Still very swollen.
아직도 많이 부어있습니다.
hurry up. Let's apply some more medicine.
서둘러요. 약을 더 바르자.
Honey,
꿀,
That guy is bad news.
그 사람은 나쁜 소식이에요.
WHO？
WHO?
that person.
저 사람.
I don't want you to see him.
나는 당신이 그를 보는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
What happened to him?
그에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
You spilled the tea yourself,
당신이 직접 차를 쏟았잖아요.
Then you disrespectfully threw the cloth away
그럼 넌 무례하게 천을 던져버렸지
He handed it to you.
그는 그것을 당신에게 건네주었습니다.
It seems that you are someone who needs to pay attention to your attitude.
당신은 태도에 주의를 기울여야 할 사람인 것 같습니다 .
I will pay attention to my attitude.
나는 내 태도에 주의를 기울일 것이다.
I will be a very nice person.
나는 아주 좋은 사람이 될 것이다.
I will try to learn how to read
나는 읽는 법을 배우려고 노력할 것이다
and astrology.
그리고 점성술.
I will also make a lot of money.
저도 돈 많이 벌겠습니다.
Please do not? ? ?
이러지마 제발? ? ?
- Please do not? ? ? - What?
- 이러지마 제발? ? ? - 무엇?
Don't leave me for someone else.
다른 사람을 위해 나를 떠나지 마십시오.
When did I say I was leaving you to find someone else?
내가 언제 당신을 떠나 다른 사람을 찾겠다고 말했습니까?
Plus, you don't have to work that hard.
게다가 그렇게 열심히 일할 필요도 없습니다.
Do you still remember what I said when I was in Rongcheng?
내가 룽청에 있을 때 한 말을 아직도 기억하시나요?
Rong Yu, listen. No matter what happens,
유롱, 들어보세요. 무슨 일이 있어도
No matter what you become,
당신이 무엇이 되든,
You are always the best to me.
당신은 나에게 항상 최고입니다.
This wasn't always the case.
항상 그런 것은 아니었습니다.
Remember when I said I was going to take time off?
내가 잠시 쉬겠다고 말했던 거 기억나?
What I said was not entirely true.
내가 말한 것은 전적으로 사실이 아닙니다.
I just wanted to annoy you.
난 단지 당신을 괴롭히고 싶었어요.
I hope you can laugh when you are happy
기쁠 때 웃을 수 있기를 바랍니다
Cry when you are feeling down.
기분이 우울할 때는 울어보세요.
If you are in a bad mood,
기분이 좋지 않다면,
You can vent to me.
당신은 나에게 화를 낼 수 있습니다.
If you want to lie to me, that's okay.
나에게 거짓말을 하고 싶다면 괜찮습니다.
You don’t have to be the best young master in Jialin
Jialin 최고의 젊은 스승이 될 필요는 없습니다
Nor is he the young master of Xingxiang Pavilion.
그는 Xingxiang Pavilion의 젊은 주인도 아닙니다.
You are just Rong Yu.
당신은 단지 Rong Yu입니다.
So just be yourself.
그러니 그냥 자신이 되십시오.
If you want to learn reading or astrology
독서나 점성술을 배우고 싶다면
Go for it.
그것을 위해 가십시오.
But if not, no big deal.
하지만 그렇지 않다면 별 문제가 되지 않습니다.
I just want you to be happy.
나는 단지 당신이 행복하기를 바랍니다.
If you want to become better,
더 나아지고 싶다면,
I will do whatever it takes to heal you.
나는 당신을 치료하기 위해 필요한 모든 것을 할 것입니다.
As long as you are happy.
당신이 행복하다면.
As for making money,
돈 버는 일에 관해서는,
If Rong's goes bankrupt
롱이 파산하면
I will hit the road
나는 길을 갈 것이다
And become a female knight to support you.
그리고 당신을 지원하는 여성 기사가 되십시오.
Miss,
놓치다,
Teacher Rong, how are you?
롱 선생님, 잘 지내세요?
and Zhangping
그리고 장핑
doing?
행위?
Hey, well done everyone.
안녕하세요, 모두들 수고하셨어요.
Teacher Rong is studying
롱 선생님은 공부 중이에요
more words
더 많은 단어
every day,
매일,
He's been smiling a lot lately.
그 사람은 최근에 많이 웃고 있어요.
He also asked Zhanping
그는 또한 Zhanping에게 물었다.
If you come back after New Year.
설날 이후에 다시 오신다면.
I have a new maid.
나에겐 새 하녀가 생겼어요.
Her martial arts skills are indeed very high
무술 실력이 정말 대단하네요
So no need to worry
그러니 걱정할 필요 없어
Mr. Rong and Zhan Ping were bullied.
Rong 씨와 Zhan Ping 씨는 괴롭힘을 당했습니다.
Zhan Ping has to scold you.
Zhan Ping이 당신을 꾸짖어야 합니다.
Several times a day.
하루에 여러 번.
I don’t know what Heshan is doing recently.
허샨이 최근에 무엇을 하고 있는지 모르겠어요.
Because he's been gone for so long.
왜냐면 그 사람은 너무 오랫동안 떠나 있었거든요.
Didn't even come back for the New Year
새해에도 돌아오지 않았어
Even though the young master was so kind to him before.
예전에는 젊은 주인이 그에게 너무 친절했지만.
Don't come back. Don't come back.
돌아오지 마세요. 돌아오지 마세요.
He was so angry that you left without taking care of Mr. Rong.
그는 너무 화가 나서 당신이 롱 씨를 돌보지 않고 떠났습니다.
within a few months,
몇 달 안에,
When Master Rong is no longer angry
Master Rong이 더 이상 화를 내지 않을 때
Or when Master Rong’s condition improves,
아니면 롱 선생님의 상태가 좋아지면
I'll let him talk to Master Rong
그에게 Master Rong과 대화하게 할게요.
You are allowed to go home.
당신은 집에 갈 수 있습니다.
You once told me that you are small,
예전에 당신이 작다고 말했잖아요.
After a while no one will remember you.
시간이 지나면 아무도 당신을 기억하지 못할 것입니다.
However, even if time passes,
그러나 시간이 흘러도
those who really care about you
당신을 정말로 걱정하는 사람들
will always remember
항상 기억할 것이다
And I miss you more and more.
그리고 나는 당신을 점점 더 그리워합니다.
Happy New Year!
새해 복 많이 받으세요!
Wish you all the best.
최선을 다하길 바랍니다.
What is your New Year's resolution?
당신의 새해 결심은 무엇입니까?
Don't worry if this is difficult.
이것이 어렵다면 걱정하지 마세요.
i will find a way
내가 방법을 찾아볼게
Help you achieve this goal
이 목표를 달성하도록 도와주세요
I don't have any wishes
난 아무 소원도 없어
how so?
어떻게 그래?
You must have some wishes. Even Zhan Ping has aspirations.
소원이 좀 있으실 텐데요. 잔핑(Zhan Ping)에게도 야망이 있습니다.
The lady gave me two gold bars.
그 여자는 나에게 금괴 두 개를 주었다.
Even the one from Heshan was given to me.
하산에서 온 것도 나에게 주어졌습니다.
This will irritate him.
이것은 그를 짜증나게 할 것입니다.
Newcomer, what is your wish?
신입생 여러분, 소원이 무엇인가요?
She's been here for a while
그녀는 여기에 한동안 있었어
And said nothing.
그리고 아무 말도 하지 않았습니다.
Is she mute?
그 사람이 벙어리인가요?
It doesn't matter if you don't speak.
말을 안 해도 상관없습니다.
You'd better not speak.
말하지 않는 것이 좋습니다.
Her name is Cheng Bi.
그녀의 이름은 청비(Cheng Bi)입니다.
C-Chengbi.
C-쳉비.
This name is really hard to remember.
이 이름은 정말 기억하기 어렵습니다.
What? ? ?
무엇? ? ?
What is your wish?
당신의 소원은 무엇입니까?
It's all happening.
모든 일이 일어나고 있습니다.
[Gongsun's Mansion]
[공순저택]
Why cancel hunting plans?
왜 사냥 계획을 취소하나요?
Your Majesty,
폐하,
A murder recently occurred in the capital
최근 수도에서 살인 사건이 발생했습니다.
It remains unresolved.
아직 해결되지 않은 상태입니다.
This makes everyone anxious.
이것이 모두를 불안하게 만든다.
For the safety of His Majesty,
폐하의 안전을 위해,
I think it's better to stay in the palace.
궁전에 머무르는 것이 더 낫다고 생각합니다.
So what do you mean
그럼 무슨 말이에요?
As long as I step out of the palace, I will be killed.
내가 궁궐 밖으로 나가기만 하면 나는 죽임을 당할 것이다.
Your Majesty,
폐하,
I? ? ?
나? ? ?
I'm just worried.
그냥 걱정이에요.
Worry?
걱정하다?
Are you so useless?
당신은 그렇게 쓸모가 없나요?
We hold spring exams to select military attachés? ?
무관을 선발하기 위해 봄 시험을 본다고요? ?
and Jinwu guards.
그리고 진우 경비병.
Did you elect a bunch of losers?
패자들을 뽑았나요?
They couldn't even catch the suspect.
용의자를 잡지도 못했습니다.
Maybe, we should hold another martial arts exam.
아마도 무술 시험을 다시 치뤄야 할 것 같습니다.
Hunt at the same time.
동시에 사냥하십시오.
- I want to hand-pick people. - Yes, Your Majesty.
- 사람을 직접 뽑고 싶어요. - 예, 폐하.
So we don't need to cancel the hunt at all.
따라서 사냥을 전혀 취소할 필요가 없습니다.
Send more people there then
그럼 더 많은 사람을 그곳으로 보내세요
Follow His Majesty.
폐하를 따르십시오.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
That's a good idea, uncle.
좋은 생각이에요, 삼촌.
So let's do that.
그럼 그렇게 해보자.
I see.
알겠어요.
Hunting plans all settled.
사냥 계획이 모두 확정되었습니다.
Don't bother me with this anymore.
더 이상 이런 일로 나를 괴롭히지 마세요.
Uncle, why are you here?
삼촌, 왜 여기 있어요?
I'm leaving now, Your Majesty.
저는 이제 떠나겠습니다, 폐하.
Your Majesty.
폐하.
Recently, Mr. Qian from the salt transportation department,
최근 소금운송과의 Qian씨가
assassinated.
암살됨.
Does your Majesty know about this?
폐하께서는 이 사실을 알고 계십니까?
The matter has been reported to the Department of Revenue and Population .
이 문제는 세입인구부에 보고되었습니다 .
I have arranged for someone to comfort his family.
나는 그의 가족을 위로할 사람을 마련했습니다 .
Incidentally,
그런데,
Department of Justice and Department of Income and Population
법무부 및 소득인구부
Efforts have been made to catch the perpetrators, but without success.
범인을 잡기 위해 노력했지만 성공하지 못했습니다.
They did find the old guy
그들은 그 늙은 남자를 찾았어요
Misappropriating a large amount of salt tax.
막대한 양의 소금세를 유용하고 있습니다.
I don't actually care about this
사실 난 이런 건 신경 안 써
So I sent them to you.
그래서 나는 그것들을 당신에게 보냈습니다.
You don't blame me, do you?
당신은 나를 비난하지 않습니다, 그렇죠?
How can this be?
어떻게 이럴 수있어?
It's the minister's job
장관의 일이네
To relieve the emperor's worries.
황제의 걱정을 덜어드리기 위해.
If possible, could you also try it?
가능하다면 당신도 시도해 볼 수 있나요?
Recover misappropriated salt taxes?
유용된 소금세를 회수하시겠습니까?
Then,
그 다음에,
There's nothing more for me to do.
내가 더 이상 할 일은 없습니다.
Not really.
설마.
It's time to change managers
이제 관리자를 바꿀 시간이다
for several salt pans
여러 개의 소금 냄비에 대해
The latest report from Sichuan stated that
쓰촨성(Sichuan)의 최신 보고서에 따르면
They discovered vast salt pans.
그들은 광대한 염전을 발견했습니다.
The salt tax was vital to the economy.
소금세는 경제에 매우 중요했습니다.
So the salt luck makes this position super important.
그래서 소금운이 이 위치를 매우 중요하게 만듭니다.
I come to see your majesty today
오늘은 폐하를 만나러 왔어요
Just wanted to ask
그냥 물어보고 싶었어
If you have a candidate in mind
염두에 두고 있는 후보가 있다면
As the salt transport envoy.
소금 수송 사절로서.
Excellent,
훌륭한,
Can you help me decide?
제가 결정하는 것을 도와주실 수 있나요?
This matter is crucial,
이 문제는 매우 중요합니다.
So I want to hear your Majesty's opinion.
그래서 폐하의 의견을 듣고 싶습니다.
The Salt Transportation Department is the main tax department.
소금운수부가 주요 세무부서이다.
The previous salt transport envoy embezzled so much money.
전직 소금운송사절이 너무 많은 돈을 횡령했습니다.
It seems I really need
정말 필요한 것 같아요
Consider candidates carefully.
후보자를 신중하게 고려하십시오.
I thought General Yan’s second son,
연 장군의 둘째 아들이라고 생각했는데,
Yan Jin may be a good choice.
Yan Jin이 좋은 선택일 수 있습니다.
Even though he is new to the Ministry of Taxation and Population
비록 그가 조세인구부에 새로 왔음에도 불구하고
his father and eldest brother
그의 아버지와 큰 형
He has considerable prestige in the military.
그는 군대에서 상당한 명성을 가지고 있습니다.
He must be very capable
그 사람은 매우 능력이 있을 거야
And not afraid of offending others.
그리고 다른 사람에게 상처를 주는 것을 두려워하지 않습니다.
He should be entrusted with important tasks.
그에게는 중요한 임무가 맡겨져야 한다.
I understand your Majesty's intention,
폐하의 뜻을 이해합니다.
I will consider it carefully.
신중하게 고려하겠습니다.
Hot water is coming.
뜨거운 물이 나옵니다.
This medicine needs to be taken once a day for five days.
이 약은 5일 동안 하루에 한 번 복용해야 합니다 .
Then you will become super smart
그러면 당신은 정말 똑똑해질 거예요
Well-known astrologer
유명한 점성가
Why does this pill fizz?
이 알약은 왜 거품이 나는 걸까요?
This is a bit strange.
이것은 조금 이상합니다.
Madam, there will be nothing wrong with this medicine, right?
부인, 이 약은 아무 이상없겠죠 ?
This medicine should be fine.
이 약은 괜찮을 것 같아요.
I've tried it myself
제가 직접 시도해 봤습니다
But I'm still worried about his frail health.
하지만 나는 여전히 그의 허약한 건강이 걱정된다.
So I split the doses.
그래서 복용량을 나누었습니다.
Don't go to an astrology center
점성술 센터에 가지 마세요
Just stay home for the next few days.
앞으로 며칠 동안은 그냥 집에 있어주세요.
This way I can always take care of him.
이렇게 하면 내가 항상 그 사람을 돌볼 수 있어요.
This is the last day.
오늘이 마지막 날입니다.
we will find
우리는 찾을 것이다
If Master Rong recovers
마스터 롱이 회복되면
When he wakes up this time, right?
이번에는 그가 깨어났을 때죠?
He will definitely recover!
그는 반드시 회복될 것입니다!
Miss He.
미스 헤.
Take good care of him.
그를 잘 돌봐주세요.
Miss Tan is here
미스 탄이 여기 있어요
You go make some soup now.
이제 수프를 만드세요.
When Master Rong woke up,
롱 선생님이 깨어났을 때,
He will definitely be hungry.
그는 분명히 배가 고플 것입니다.
OK
좋아요
Rigorous investigation is currently underway.
현재 철저한 조사가 진행 중이다.
Don't take any action yet.
아직 아무런 조치도 취하지 마세요.
Wait for my news
내 소식을 기다려
How are you?
어떻게 지내세요?
I am fine.
괜찮아요.
everything is fine.
모든 것이 괜찮습니다.
You always say that.
당신은 항상 그렇게 말해요.
It would be great if I knew martial arts
무술을 알면 참 좋을텐데
I can protect you rain or shine.
비가오나 눈이오나 나는 당신을 보호할 수 있습니다.
Everything you have done for me is enough.
당신이 나에게 하신 모든 일은 충분합니다.
I don't want to drag you into this mess.
나는 당신을 이 혼란 속으로 끌고 싶지 않습니다.
When all this is done,
이 모든 작업이 완료되면
We can do anything you want.
우리는 당신이 원하는 무엇이든 할 수 있습니다.
I will support you no matter what, even if it means risking my life.
목숨을 걸고서라도 꼭 응원하겠습니다 .
Don't say that.
그렇게 말하지 마세요.
We all need to be safe and healthy.
우리 모두는 안전하고 건강해야 합니다.
I mean everyone.
내 말은 모두를 의미합니다.
you told me last time
지난번에 나한테 말했잖아
I heard you found a cure for Master Rong.
롱 사부의 치료법을 찾았다고 들었습니다.
How is he now?
그는 지금은 어떤가요?
Really? if he gets better
정말? 그 사람이 좋아지면
you can make a deal
당신은 거래를 할 수 있습니다
And together, right?
그리고 함께, 그렇죠?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
There is no such thing as a deal.
거래 같은 것은 없습니다.
Now,
지금,
I just wish him the best.
나는 그에게 최선을 다하길 바랄 뿐입니다.
If it were the past, I would believe it.
과거라면 믿었을 텐데.
Now you and Master Rong
이제 당신과 Master Rong
Looks really in love.
정말 사랑에 빠진 것 같습니다.
don't make fun of me
나를 놀리지 마세요
related to this matter.
이 문제와 관련이 있습니다.
He is just a child,
그는 단지 어린아이일 뿐이고,
And don’t really understand things yet.
그리고 아직은 내용을 잘 이해하지 못합니다.
He is close to me and dependent on me.
그는 나와 가깝고 나에게 의존합니다.
Because he only treats me as family.
그 사람은 나를 가족으로만 대하기 때문이다.
He helped me and protected me,
나를 도우시고 보호해 주셨는데,
even saved me
심지어 나를 구해줬어
When the He family encountered changes.
He 가족이 변화를 겪었을 때.
Emotionally and rationally,
감정적으로나 이성적으로나
He should be the most important person to me.
그 사람은 나에게 가장 중요한 사람이어야 해요.
I should always cherish him and protect him.
나는 항상 그를 소중히 여기고 보호해야 한다.
But this life,
하지만 이번 생은,
I owe him so much.
나는 그에게 너무 많은 빚을 지고 있습니다.
I could never fully repay him.
나는 그에게 결코 완전히 갚을 수 없었습니다.
I've thought about it.
나는 그것에 대해 생각했습니다.
When he recovered,
그가 회복되었을 때,
Even without me,
나 없이도,
he will still be
그는 여전히 그럴 것이다
Young Master of Xingxiang Pavilion
Xingxiang Pavilion의 젊은 스승
No one dares to bully.
누구도 감히 괴롭히지 못합니다.
We will go our separate ways.
우리는 각자의 길을 갈 것입니다.
After all, we weren't supposed to be together in the first place.
결국, 우리는 애초에 함께 있을 생각이 아니었습니다.
There is no need to continue to deceive yourself.
계속해서 자신을 속일 필요는 없습니다.
As such a gentleman,
그런 신사로서,
If one day he
만약 어느 날 그 사람이
Discover
발견하다
In his most difficult time,
그의 가장 어려운 시기에,
i abandoned him
나는 그를 버렸어
And then married him as the daughter of a criminal
그리고 그와 범죄자의 딸로 결혼했습니다.
To save myself,
나 자신을 구하기 위해,
He would have been absolutely disgusted.
그는 정말 역겨워했을 것입니다.
Even if he doesn't say anything,
그 사람이 아무 말도 안 해도,
How can I keep Mrs. Rong's name?
Rong 부인의 이름을 어떻게 유지할 수 있습니까?
And drag him down?
그리고 그를 아래로 끌어내리나요?
But you are not that person.
하지만 당신은 그런 사람이 아닙니다.
Who cares if you are?
당신이라면 누가 신경쓰나요?
None of this matters.
이 중 어느 것도 중요하지 않습니다.
What's important is that
중요한 것은
you have to ask yourself
스스로에게 물어봐야 해
Have you never liked Master Yung?
Master Yung을 좋아한 적이 없나요?
I don't.
나는 아니에요.
I'm going back to my room now.
나는 이제 내 방으로 돌아갈 예정이다.
Teacher Rong,
롱 선생님,
haven't seen you for a long time.
오랫동안 당신을 보지 못했습니다.
Honey, I've been here a long time.
여보, 나 여기 온 지 꽤 오래됐어.
I saw the moon a minute ago
조금 전에 달을 봤어요
but i don't know why
그런데 왜 그런지 모르겠어요
It disappears.
그것은 사라진다.
master? ? ?
주인? ? ?
Master Rong.
롱 선생님.
What?
무엇?
Why do you call me that?
왜 나를 그렇게 부르나요?
5 years? ? ?
5 년? ? ?
Five years have passed.
5년이 지났습니다.
I'm sure it will work this time.
이번에는 성공할 것이라고 확신합니다.
Why does it still not work?
왜 아직도 작동하지 않나요?
If it doesn't work this time
이번에도 안되면
I really don't know what to do.
나는 정말로 무엇을 해야할지 모르겠습니다.
All because I was useless.
모두 내가 쓸모없었기 때문이다.
sorry.
죄송합니다.
Hey, please don't cry, okay?
야, 제발 울지 마, 알았지?
I am still the same Rong Yu.
나는 여전히 같은 Rong Yu입니다.
or maybe
아니면 아마도
You don't like it either
너도 마음에 안 들어
This Rong Yu who doesn’t understand anything,
아무것도 이해하지 못하는 이 롱유,
do not understand anything,
아무것도 이해하지 못해요,
nothing can be done
아무것도 할 수 없어
For you.
당신을 위한.
Don't say that about yourself.
자신에 대해 그런 말을 하지 마세요.
You are always the best.
당신은 항상 최고입니다.
No matter what happens,
무슨 일이 있어도
No matter what you become,
당신이 무엇이 되든,
You are always the best Rongyu.
당신은 항상 최고의 Rongyu입니다.
Really?
정말?
So why? ? ?
왜? ? ?
why are you crying?
왜 울고 있어요?
I won't cry anymore.
나는 더 이상 울지 않을 것이다.
The moon is gone,
달은 사라졌고,
But the stars are still there.
하지만 별은 여전히 ​​거기에 있다.
hurry up. Let's go stargazing
서둘러요. 별 보러 가자
look.
바라보다.
No wonder you like stargazing so much.
당신이 별 관찰을 그토록 좋아하는 것도 당연합니다.
Even though I can't know my fate,
내 운명을 알 수 없어도
Still looks beautiful.
여전히 아름다워 보입니다.
How come I didn't notice this before?
왜 내가 전에 이것을 눈치 채지 못했습니까?
look! look! A shooting star!
바라보다! 바라보다! 슈팅스타!
I've tied the knot for you. make a wish.
나는 당신을 위해 매듭을 묶었습니다. 소원을 말해봐.
When you see a shooting star,
별똥별을 보면,
tie a knot in your clothes
옷에 매듭을 묶어라
Then make a wish.
그럼 소원을 빌어보세요.
Then, God will hear your wishes.
그러면 하나님께서 여러분의 소원을 들어주실 것입니다.
Then God will help you achieve it
그러면 하나님께서 당신이 그것을 성취하도록 도와주실 것입니다.
I've done it for you.
나는 당신을 위해 그것을했습니다.
Just make a wish.
소원을 빌어보세요.
i wish i could see my wife
내 아내를 볼 수 있으면 좋겠어
every day
매일
Never leave her.
절대 그녀를 떠나지 마세요.
Is this your wish?
이것이 당신의 소원인가요?
are you still thinking
아직도 생각하고 있어?
will i leave you?
내가 당신을 떠날까요?
i want my husband
나는 내 남편을 원해요
will live a safe and healthy life,
안전하고 건강한 삶을 살게 될 것입니다.
become
~이 되다
A wizard who lived to be a hundred years old.
백세까지 살았던 마법사.
return,
반품,
I hope
나는 희망
My husband can bully others
남편이 다른 사람을 괴롭힐 수 있어요
But no one can bully him.
하지만 누구도 그를 괴롭힐 수는 없습니다.
I also hope that? ? ?
나도 그랬으면 좋겠어? ? ?
Rong Yu, look! Meteor shower!
롱 유,보세요! 유성우!
Although the moon is gone, the stars are still there.
달은 사라졌지만 별은 여전히 ​​거기에 있다.
If you can't recover,
회복할 수 없다면,
I will be with you.
나는 너랑있을 꺼야.
Rong Yu,
유 롱,
I will never leave you.
나는 결코 당신을 떠나지 않을 것입니다.
Do not be afraid.
두려워 하지마.
A deposed emperor and a female general.
폐위된 황제와 여성 장군.
It's hard outside,
밖은 힘들고,
I'm not even sure where we're going.
우리가 어디로 가는지조차 모르겠습니다.
over there.
저기.
Actually,
실제로,
I can't promise you anything.
나는 당신에게 아무것도 약속할 수 없습니다.
I promise you
약속 할게
Come back after dinner
저녁 식사 후에 다시 오세요
but I do not have.
하지만 나는 가지고 있지 않습니다.
I promise you
약속 할게
I won't leave you alone
나는 당신을 혼자 두지 않을 것입니다
In the capital,
수도에서는
I will always protect you
나는 항상 당신을 보호 할 것입니다
but I do not have.
하지만 나는 가지고 있지 않습니다.
The future is uncertain.
미래는 불확실하다.
Neither can I? ? ?
나도 못해? ? ?
I can't even promise you
약속할 수도 없어
I won't leave you again.
나는 다시는 당신을 떠나지 않을 것입니다.
if i'm no longer here
내가 더 이상 여기에 없다면
And neither is Mr. Rong,
그리고 롱 씨도 마찬가지예요.
Who else in the world
세상에 또 누가 있어?
Can I accompany and protect you?
내가 당신과 동행하고 보호해 줄 수 있을까요?
I can't leave you alone.
나는 당신을 내버려 둘 수 없습니다.
I know how hard it is to get through it alone
혼자서 이겨내기가 얼마나 힘든지 알아요
So I don't want you to go through this again.
그래서 나는 당신이 이런 일을 다시 겪지 않기를 바랍니다.
Rong Yu,
유 롱,
Do you want to? ? ?
원하시나요? ? ?
want to? ? ?
고 싶어요? ? ?
Have one? ? ?
하나 갖고 계십니까? ? ?
Cover yourself well. It's cold.
몸을 잘 감싸세요. 추워.
Zhanping, come here.
잔핑, 이리 와봐.
I have something to say to you.
당신에게 할 말이 있습니다.
[Gongsun's Mansion]
[공순저택]
The Regent's daughter had just been given a princess.
리전트의 딸에게 방금 공주가 주어졌습니다.
Xunnan sent a message
Xunnan이 메시지를 보냈습니다.
The purpose is to marry the princess.
목적은 공주와 결혼하는 것이다.
The Prince Regent was certainly excited.
Prince Regent는 확실히 흥분했습니다.
They were all prepared for this,
이에 대해 모두들 준비가 되어 있었고,
And too busy to care about anything else.
그리고 너무 바빠서 다른 것에 신경 쓸 여유도 없습니다.
Now the Regent's people are falling apart.
이제 리젠트의 사람들은 무너지고 있습니다.
He can only use military symbols to bluff people.
그는 사람들에게 허세를 부리기 위해 군사 상징만을 사용할 수 있습니다.
Wang Dequan,
왕 더취안,
How many days until the hunt?
사냥까지 며칠 남았나요?
Three days.
삼 일.
Grinding ink. I need to write a letter.
연삭 잉크. 편지를 써야 해요.
From Heshan.
허산 출신.
He won't be back for a while.
그는 한동안 돌아오지 않을 것이다.
[To Zhangping]
[장핑에게]
How could Heshan do this?
허샨은 어떻게 이런 일을 할 수 있었나요?
He has been home for so long and still hasn't come back.
그 사람은 집에 온 지 너무 오래됐는데 아직도 돌아오지 않더라고요.
Does he not miss Master Rong at all?
그는 롱 사부를 전혀 그리워하지 않습니까?
It's not his fault.
그의 잘못이 아닙니다.
I should go talk to my uncle.
가서 삼촌한테 얘기 좀 해야겠다.
OK By the way, Teacher Rong,
좋아요 그런데 롱 선생님,
Last time you asked me -
저번에 나한테 물어봤잖아 -
I'll go to the kitchen to make soup first.
먼저 부엌에 가서 수프를 만들게요.
Do you have anything to say?
할 말 있어?
check it out.
확인 해봐.
What's this?
이건 뭐죠?
I can't wake you up.
나는 당신을 깨울 수 없습니다.
Think of it this way.
이렇게 생각해보세요.
if you could have someone
누군가를 가질 수 있다면
Be as smart and cute as me by your side
나만큼 똑똑하고 귀엽게 옆에 있어줘
Then, even if one day I am not around.
그러면 어느 날 내가 곁에 없더라도.
He Jiuling.
He Jiuling.
If you're not around, I'll be alone.
당신이 주변에 없으면 나 혼자 있을 거예요.
Can you stop being so childish?
너무 유치하게 굴지 말아줄래?
This is the best promise
이것이 최고의 약속이다
I can give it to you.
나는 당신에게 그것을 줄 수 있습니다.
- I'm going for a walk. - where are you going?
- 산책하러 갈 거예요. - 어디 가세요?
???Under the sunset at dusk? ? ?
???해질녘 노을 아래서요? ? ?
???I traveled thousands of miles to a distant place? ? ?
???나는 먼 곳으로 수천 마일을 여행했다고요? ? ?
???Playing the piano under the moonlight? ? ?
???달빛아래 피아노 연주? ? ?
???These drinks won’t make me forget? ? ?
???이 음료수는 잊혀지지 않을까요? ? ?
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
???내가 당신을 위해 쓴 소망은요? ? ?
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있다고? ? ?
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 최강의 와인을 좋아하시나요? ? ?
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 운명을 피할 방법은 없나요? ? ?
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
???뒤돌아보니 기다리고 있는거 보이시죠? ? ?
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
???우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니까? ? ?
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 밝은 은하계로 결정화되기를 원하시나요 ???
???You quietly turned around and closed the marriage certificate? ? ?
??? 조용히 돌아서서 결혼증명서를 닫았나요? ? ?
???Ask how many stars are there in the sky? ? ?
???하늘에 별이 몇 개 있는지 물어보세요. ? ?
???The desire I wrote for you? ? ?
???내가 당신을 위해 쓴 소망은요? ? ?
??? Our destiny is written on paper? ? ?
??? 우리의 운명은 종이에 적혀있다고? ? ?
??? Like the strongest wine? ? ?
??? 최강의 와인을 좋아하시나요? ? ?
??? There is no way to escape fate? ? ?
??? 운명을 피할 방법은 없나요? ? ?
???Looking back, I saw you waiting? ? ?
???뒤돌아보니 기다리고 있는거 보이시죠? ? ?
???Our life is full of joy and sorrow? ? ?
???우리의 삶은 기쁨과 슬픔으로 가득 차 있습니까? ? ?
??? Desire to crystallize into a bright galaxy???
??? 밝은 은하계로 결정화되기를 원하시나요 ???
???I gently caress the guzheng, waiting for passers-by like you???
???나는 고젱을 부드럽게 어루만지며 당신같은 행인을 기다린다???
???So you are my indissoluble bond? ? ?
???그럼 당신은 나의 불용성 유대인가요? ? ?